Hello everyone and welcome back
to another lesson here at English Pod.
My name is Marco and my name is Katherine.
So Marco what are we talking about today?
Today we're talking about
a very interesting topic.
You've probably seen it on every TV show or
American movie and it's a bachelor party.
Uh oh.
Yeah.
I've heard bad things.
I've heard bad things
about a bachelor party.
Well they can be a
fun but at times they
can be a little bit too
excessive, too much.
But before we get started
on the dialogue why
don't we take a look
at vocabulary preview?
Very capillary preview.
Well the first we've got
here is the topic of today.
This is the bachelor party.
So what is a bachelor or exactly?
Right.
Well a bachelor is a
person who is not married,
a single person, a
single guy specifically.
All right.
So it's a man.
Before he's married.
Right.
You would say a bachelorette.
Okay.
Bachelor is a guy and
a bachelorette is a girl.
And so we don't really say bachelorette
except when we're talking about this party.
Right.
So a bachelor party is a party that a guy
has the day before he's married or maybe
two or three days before
he actually gets married.
So it's a night where all
his friends get together.
They go out.
They have some drinks.
They have some fun.
And just like the last
extreme fun, they will
have, he will have
before he gets married.
All right.
And so it's all his guy friends.
All his guy friends.
Only guys, no girls.
And the bachelor at
party is only girls and
it's when a girl's friends
take her out before
she gets married to celebrate her
last night or two of being unmarried.
Right.
Exactly.
So not only guys, parties
can get a little bit crazy, but
girls, bachelorette parties
can also get kind of crazy, right?
That's true.
So before we start
talking about what exactly
goes on at some
of these parties, let's
take a listen to today's dialogue and
hear what happens to our main character.
Hi, honey.
You'll never guess what?
My friends, Julian Alex,
are getting married.
Wow.
That's great news.
They're a great couple.
I know.
Anyways, I just talked to Alex's best man
and he is organizing the bachelor party.
It's going to be so much fun.
All the groomsmen
are thinking of all the
wacky and crazy things
we're going to do that night.
You aren't going to a strip club, are you?
I don't want you getting
a laugh dance from
some stripper with
the excuse that it's your
friend's party.
Ah, come on.
It's just some innocent fun.
You know how these things are.
We're going to play
drinking games, get them
some gag gifts and
just have a good time.
Going to over the top.
Well, I don't know.
Come on.
If one of your friends
was getting married, I
wouldn't mind you going
to a bachelor at party.
Good, because my friend Wendy is getting
married and I'm organizing her party.
What?
All right, great.
So apparently both of
them have parties to go
to, but I don't think the
guy was too happy about it.
I don't think so either.
And that's the funny thing.
I think a lot of girls are like, oh, well,
my husband to be, he wants to have a party.
It's okay.
But the minute the girl wants to have
the party, the guy is like, ah, ah, no way.
That's true.
I guess.
But we can talk a little bit
more about this towards the end.
Before we start on
this really interesting
topic, why don't we take a look at some
of the language on language takeaway.
Well, Marco, the first
few words are actually
more wedding terms
than bachelor party terms.
The first one is best man.
Right.
The best man.
So the best man is who is he exactly?
He's usually the groom's best friend.
So the groom is the
man getting married and
his best friend has the
position of best man.
So he has some special
things to do with the wedding.
He has to make a speech,
for example, and he has to
stand next to his friend
when the friend gets married.
And it's just a very
special position of
honor that the best friend
has in his friend's wedding.
Okay.
And among those responsibilities,
the best man is usually
the one that has to organize
the bachelor party, right?
Exactly.
Okay.
So best man.
And well, the rest of the groom's
friends are also present at the wedding.
And they are called the groomsmen.
All right, so groom groomsmen.
And so usually these
are maybe three to five
guys, three to five
men, who are friends
of the groom or brother of the
bride, it depends on the wedding.
And they stand with the
man when he gets married.
And so they kind of have a
lot of responsibilities as well.
Okay.
And the groomsmen usually are
also present at the bachelor party.
Exactly.
All right.
Now moving on to a bit
more colorful language.
We have a place here, a strip club.
Okay.
So sometimes you see
these in movies oftentimes.
So for example, the TV show, the Sopranos.
This is often a place where Tony
Soprano goes, a strip club is a club.
It's like a bar.
It's open most of the
day and night where there
are women who take
their clothes off for money.
All right.
So you have the verb
to strip, right, a strip club.
So the verb to strip means to
take off or leave without something.
Right.
So you can strip off your clothes.
So it's usually used with clothes,
right, to take off clothes, to strip.
So you have a strip
club and in the strip
club, you have the, as
you mentioned, the girls
that are dancing and taking off
their clothes, they are called strippers.
Okay.
So stripper is a person who
takes off their clothes as their job.
And you can have male
strippers or female strippers.
So usually just saying stripper is a woman
and a male stripper is actually a guy.
Okay.
So you have this club
that's very common in many
countries and will the
strippers are dancing.
And now they also talked
about getting a lap dance.
Okay.
Now this is getting
a little bit, a little
dirty lap is a, well, it's not
really a part of your body.
But when you sit down in a chair,
your lap is the tops of your legs.
So you can, you know, you can hold something
in your lap like your backpack or maybe
for example, if you
have a child that's three
or four years old, you
would sit him on your
lap, right, on your legs while
you're sitting down maybe in sub way.
Right.
Or a laptop computer is the kind of
computer you can hold on your lap.
So a lap dance is
when one of the female
strippers comes and
kind of dances on your lap.
Exactly.
And so it's a sexy dance.
You pay for it extra
and it's something that
is very popular with a
young man and people
who, you know, these grooms and
grooms men before the groom gets married.
Right.
All right.
And moving on, we have the
last word for today, gag gifts.
All right, gag gifts are joke gifts.
They're, they're meant to be funny.
They're not meant to be serious.
All right.
And they're very popular at these kinds of
bachelor parties and bachelor at parties.
One kind of gag gift that's just
very silly is like a whoopie cushion.
You know, it's like a, it's like a
balloon you put on someone's seat.
And when they sit down,
they rest a farting sound.
Right.
So those are gag gifts.
Anything that's kind
of for, to joke around,
it's not really used for us not like
giving somebody a t-shirt, right?
Right.
Or a gift card is a nice gift.
It's not, it's not a gag gift.
Right.
So there are really, there are a
lot of different types of gag gifts.
And actually some of
them are pretty good and
funny, like a, you know, like spicy
chewing gum or, or the electric shocker.
Oh, yeah.
When you shake somebody's hand.
That's really funny.
All right.
So we've taken a look at a lot
of words on language takeaway.
So let's listen to this dialogue again and
we'll be right back with fluency builder.
Hi, honey, you'll never guess what?
My friends, Julian Alex
are getting married.
Wow.
That's great news.
They're a great couple.
I know.
Anyways, I just talked to Alex's best man
and he is organizing the bachelor party.
It's going to be so much fun.
All the groomsmen are thinking
up all the wacky and crazy things.
We're going to do that night.
You aren't going to a strip club, are you?
I don't want you
getting a lap dance from
some stripper with
the excuse that it's your
friend's party.
Ah, come on, it's just some innocent fun.
You know how these things are.
We're going to play
drinking games, get them
some gag gifts and
just have a good time.
Nothing to over the top.
Well, I don't know.
Come on.
One of your friends was getting married.
I wouldn't mind you
going to a bachelor at party.
Good.
Because my friend Wendy's getting
married and I'm organizing her party.
What?
All right, we're back.
So now let's look at
some of the phrases that
were used in this
dialogue on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right.
So at the beginning of this dialogue, we've
meet this couple, this man and woman, and
the guy says, hey, honey,
you'll never guess what.
All right.
Okay, my friends are getting married.
So what does this mean?
You'll never guess what?
It's just a phrase that
you would use to give
really, really important
or exciting news.
It's like, guess what?
Okay.
So you'll never guess what happened to me.
Right.
I won the lottery.
It's so amazing or it's
so uncommon or unusual
that you would probably never
guess that person won the lottery.
Okay.
So you'll never guess what?
Right.
You'll never guess what?
Or you can say, guess what?
Okay.
All right.
And our second phrase, you
know how these things are.
Okay.
So this is a phrase that people
often use when they want to
remind someone that this is
tradition or it's a common thing.
And so oftentimes when
like people are having
problems at work and they say, oh gosh,
this person's just not listening to me.
Someone to help them out will say,
you know, you know how these things are.
You know, it takes some time to resolve
a problem or you could say, you know,
oh gosh, this is me horrible party.
I don't want you guys
to go to a strip club.
It's so dirty.
Right.
And you'd say, well, you know
how these things are is tradition.
You have to do it.
You have to.
Right.
So this is what he meant.
You know how these things are.
It's like, I don't really have a choice.
It's a tradition.
This is what guys do when
they're going to get married.
So we have to do it.
It's almost like saying,
don't worry about it.
There's really nothing to worry about.
Nothing to worry about.
All right.
And our last phrase and our last phrase is
something that we'd never want to happen.
Something to be over the top.
Well, it's not necessarily a bad thing.
Okay.
Right.
So we could say that it
was a really ridiculous party.
It was really over the top.
They had a clown and they had people dressed
up like star Trek characters, you know.
Something that is more than normal.
It's almost silly the
way that it's all just
kind of crazy and yeah,
it's too much in every way.
Right.
So it can be something bad.
Like for example, someone's
behavior was over the top.
It was too much.
It was too intense.
Or like, oh my gosh.
Did you see her coat?
It's really over the top.
It's like purple with sprinkles on it.
Right.
So it can be used in different ways,
but it usually means it's excessive.
It's too much.
Exactly.
All right.
So some interesting phrases
on this occasion as well.
Let's listen to our dialogue for
the last time and we'll be back.
Hi, honey, you'll never guess what.
My friends Julie and
Alex are getting married.
Wow.
That's brain news.
They're a great couple.
I know.
Anyways, I just talked to Alex's best man
and he is organizing the bachelor party.
It's going to be so much fun.
All the groomsmen
are thinking up all the
wacky and crazy things
we're going to do that night.
You aren't going to a strip club, are you?
I don't want you
getting a lap dance from
some stripper with
the excuse that it's your
friend's party.
Aw, come on.
It's just some innocent fun.
You know how these things are.
We're going to play
drinking games, get them
some gag gifts and
just have a good time.
Nothing too over the top.
Well, I don't know.
Come on.
If one of your friends
was getting married, I
wouldn't mind you going
to a bachelor at party.
Good.
With my friend Wendy's getting
married and I'm organizing her party.
What?
All right, we're back so
bachelor and bachelor at parties.
Have you ever been to a bachelor at party?
I have not yet, but one of my closest
friends is getting married a couple of weeks.
And so I will be attending and
helping organize a bachelor party.
Wow.
Do you have anything in mind?
Nothing.
I could talk about it.
These things are meant to be surprised
sometimes, so I don't want to spoil it.
But I will tell you
that my boyfriend just
organized a bachelor
party for his best friend.
He was the best man in the wedding.
Oh, OK.
And it was very crazy.
Oh, really?
Did they also go to Vegas and do some of
these things that we saw in the dialogue?
They didn't go to Vegas,
but they did some of
the things we heard
about in today's dialogue.
They went to a strip club, they
got lap dances, they drank a lot.
It was very over the top.
And I think this is
something that most of
our listeners probably
have seen in TV shows
or in movies or in
different type of exposure
of American culture,
which is actually very,
very common in Canada,
in the United States.
I'm not really sure
about Europe or England.
It is too.
Really?
My friend said that his friend was getting
married and they all went to Portugal for
a week to have a bachelor party, and I
heard something about mud wrestling.
Wow.
Well, I guess it's
different in every country.
And this is the interesting part.
We want to know how these
things are in your country.
Do you have any traditions or any fun
stuff that you do before the wedding?
Maybe after, I don't know.
What about Ecuador?
We usually don't really
have strip clubs, actually.
So it's kind of easy.
So we usually just do
what we do every night,
just go out with friends, drink and dance,
play the guitar, or yeah, maybe some gag
gifts or some prank that
we pull on the groom,
but nothing too over the top.
So yeah, we're really interested in
knowing how it is in your country.
So come to EnglishPod.com,
leave your questions,
comments, and we'll
see you guys next time.
Until then, bye everyone.
Bye.
(upbeat music)